RAJAT SRIVASTAVA

rajatsri94@gmail.com9910364830Delhiin rajatsriv19rajat19

Noida

Ghaziabad

June 2016 to July 2016

Sept. 2015 to Nov. 2015

EDUCATION

Ajay Kumar Garg Engineering College, Ghaziabad

BTech Computer Science 2017 Graduated with 80.68% Member of Open Source R&D Team Organized Tech Events in College

SUMMARY

Highly effective software developer offering a wealth of more than 3+ years of relevant expertise. A valuable team player who also is personable and dedicated. Seeking the chance to bring further success to an established organisation through development, testing, and software debugging.

SKILLS

BACKEND DEVELOPMENT: Node js(Koa/Express), Django, Java Spring

DATABASE: Mysql, Sqlite, Mongo DB **PROGRAMMING:** C, C++, Java, Python

OTHER SOFTWARES/TOOLS: Git, Redis Cache, Travis CI, Jenkins, Apache Storm, Kafka, RabbitMQ,

Grafana Monitoring, GraphQL

AWARDS

Paytm · ROCKSTAR Sept. 2020
Paytm · ROCKSTAR Oct. 2019

EMPLOYMENT

PAYTM Noida
Software Engineer Sept. 2018 to Current

- Build Paytm's Scratch Card Service
- Developed Paytm's lucky draw feature
- Worked on integration of Payment Bank's pipeline with Paytm reward system
- Developed realtime gratification and multiple gratification for Paytm's post transaction reward system
- Worked on localisation of apis for Paytm Cashback System

SMARTPRIX WEB
Software Developer

Noida
June 2017 to Aug. 2018

- Designed Node JS and Vue JS based admin web applications.
- Developed Smartprix new website using Node JS and Marko JS
- Developed Smartrank, an online IDE for test purposes
- Worked on Smartprix Crawler to extract data from appropriate websites
- Worked on Smartprix tiny url service smpx.to

SYSBIOME TECHNOLOGIES

- Created Samarpan project for recruitment purpose using Laravel framework

- Wrote all technical documentation for new software in development.
- Designed native Android mobile applications for Samarpan using Java.

JUSTWRAVEL Noida
Intern Sept. 2015 to Nov. 2015

- Worked on JustWravel.com using Codelgniter framework
- Provided continued maintenance and development of bug fixes and patch sets for existing web applications

DR. APJ ABDUL KALAM TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY

Web Developer (Contractual)

- Designed Question Paper Portal
- Received letter of appreciation from university

NISANI INDIA
Intern

Noida
May 2015 to Sept. 2015

- Applied knowledge of JavaScript and Object-Oriented Programming to create successful designs-
- Built Student ERP Portal website interface with HTML and CSS

PERSONAL PROJECTS

KEEP IN TOUCH

Application that reminds its customers to keep in touch with their dear ones. Reminders can be scheduled as per convenience.

TORRENT CRAWLER

Command line package to fetch torrents and subtitles for a movie. Hosted on pypi

HACKERRANK CRAWLER

Crawl Hackerrank Solutions using command line. Hosted on pypi

KORA

Book sharing web app using Python and Django. Hosted on heroku

GEOSEARCH

A geographical based search engine build upon Laravel Framework

TIMETABLE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

Timetable management for college using Machine Learning

Options to mark attendance for faculties